
<p>The Hedgehog tools are a set of scripts that are used to perform various tasks in terms of creating and maintaining the database and hedgehog files on disk. They can be run directly from <span>&lt;PREFIX&gt;/libexec/hedgehog or</span>&nbsp;for convenience a wrapper script (<span>&lt;PREFIX&gt;/bin/hedgehogctl</span>) is provided:</p><ac:structured-macro ac:name="code"><ac:plain-text-body><![CDATA[>hedgehogctl help
 
Run a Hedgehog command

Usage: hedgehogctl [help|list] [COMMAND] [command_options]]]></ac:plain-text-body></ac:structured-macro>
<p>The available hedgehogctl commands are described below</p>
<p><ac:structured-macro ac:name="toc" /></p>
<h2>Data Manager</h2>
<p>These scripts should be run as the DB_OWNER user (<em>hedgehog</em> by default).</p>
<h3>Database</h3>
<h4>database_init</h4>
<ul>
<li>The script should be run after the database has been created (see the &lt;prefix&gt;/libexec/database_create helper script)</li>
<li>This script populates the database with the plot and server/node data</li></ul><ac:structured-macro ac:name="code"><ac:plain-text-body><![CDATA[Create and populate the database tables with plot options and nodes.

This calls the hedeghog_database_update_nodes.sh script which will populate the DB
with the specified nodes and create a directory structure for them in the working
data directory.

Usage: database_init options

Supported options:

  -m Start month of oldest data to be imported 
     (default is current month, format YYYY-MM)
  -h Show this help]]></ac:plain-text-body></ac:structured-macro>
<h4>database_manage_partitions</h4>
<ul>
<li>
<p>This script creates new tables in the database to hold the imported data.&nbsp;</p><ac:structured-macro ac:name="warning"><ac:rich-text-body>
<p><strong>It must be run at least once a month to create the tables for next month or the import will fail. It is recommended to configure a cron job as described in the&nbsp;Cron jobs section of the Installation guide.&nbsp;</strong></p></ac:rich-text-body></ac:structured-macro></li></ul>
<ul>
<li>Otherwise, the user will only have to run this script when new servers are added to an existing system.</li></ul><ac:structured-macro ac:name="code"><ac:parameter ac:name="language">text</ac:parameter><ac:plain-text-body><![CDATA[Create a new set of partitioned data tables in the database to hold imported data.
The partitions are created per month of data.
 
Usage: database_manage_partitions options

Supported options:
    -m Month to create partitions for 
       (default is next month, format YYYY-MM)
    -h Show this help]]></ac:plain-text-body></ac:structured-macro>
<h4>database_process_rssac_data</h4>
<ul>
<li>This script should be run to process the data ready for the <em>rssac_process_data </em>script.&nbsp;</li>
<li>The importer inserts data from the XML files into the 'unique_source_raw' table. For each node, this script creates entries in the 'unique_source_summary' table based on the raw data and then (optionally) deletes the original raw data from the&nbsp;'unique_source_raw' table.</li></ul><ac:structured-macro ac:name="code"><ac:plain-text-body><![CDATA[Process RSSAC data for a specified 24 hour period
 
Usage: database_process_rssac_data options

Supported options:
  -d Date on which to process RSSAC data 
    (default is 7 days ago, format: YYYY-MM-DD)
  -f Force overwrite of existing summary data
  -D Also delete the raw unique_source data from the database to save space 
    (default: no delete)
  -h Show this help]]></ac:plain-text-body></ac:structured-macro>
<h4>database_rm_old_rssac_data</h4>
<ul>
<li>For some systems, the unique source raw data can be unmanageably large. This script can be used to truncate the database tables to recover the disk space, for example it can be run once a month to remove all the raw data for the previous month</li></ul><ac:structured-macro ac:name="code"><ac:parameter ac:name="language">text</ac:parameter><ac:plain-text-body><![CDATA[Delete all the raw unique_source data in the database for a given month. 
All data older than this is also deleted.
This script is intended to be run monthly to free disk space on systems 
where the raw unique sources data becomes unmanagably large.

Usage: database_rm_old_rssac_data options

Supported options:
  -m Month from which to delete all raw unique source data 
       (default 2014-07: format YYYY-MM)
       (default is 2 months ago when in the first half of the current month and
        1 month ago when in the second half of the current month)
  -h Show this help]]></ac:plain-text-body></ac:structured-macro>
<h4>database_update_nodes</h4>
<ul>
<li>Run this script if new nodes or servers are added to the system</li></ul><ac:structured-macro ac:name="code"><ac:parameter ac:name="language">text</ac:parameter><ac:plain-text-body><![CDATA[Add/update the servers and nodes in the database. This reads input from file
called nodes.csv in the /usr/local/etc/hedgehog directory.
 - An example nodes.csv file is installed if one does not exist.
 - See the comments in that file for details of the format.
 - No action is taken on servers/nodes that are in the database but are not in the 
   input files.

Usage: /usr/local/bin/hedgehog_database_update_nodes options

Supported options:
  -p Run in prediction mode. Output findings but don't act on the DB
  -h Show this help.]]></ac:plain-text-body></ac:structured-macro>
<h3>Datafiles</h3>
<h4>datafiles_create_summary</h4>
<ul>
<li>This is a useful utility script that can be used to get a high level picture of the processing of the XML files for all the nodes in the system. It can help identify backlogs in the processing system.</li></ul><ac:structured-macro ac:name="code"><ac:parameter ac:name="language">text</ac:parameter><ac:plain-text-body><![CDATA[Generate a processing report based on the information in the log files

Usage: datafiles_create_summary options

Supported options:
	-s Only report on the server with this name (default is all servers)
	-n Only report on the node with this name (default is all nodes)
	-c Output in csv format for import into spreadsheet application
	-h Show this help.]]></ac:plain-text-body></ac:structured-macro>
<h4>datafiles_rm_empty_xml_dirs</h4><ac:structured-macro ac:name="code"><ac:parameter ac:name="language">text</ac:parameter><ac:plain-text-body><![CDATA[Remove empty incoming xml directories after a certain period of time 
(default is all the processed directories older than 7 days ago)

Usage: datafiles_rm_empty_xml_dirs options

Supported options:
	-d Date before which removing empty xml directories 
      (default: 7 days ago, format YYYY-MM-DD)
	-h Show this help]]></ac:plain-text-body></ac:structured-macro>
<h4>datafiles_tar_old_xml_files</h4><ac:structured-macro ac:name="code"><ac:plain-text-body><![CDATA[Pack old xml files already processed into a .tar package to store and archive.
The xml files are packed according to their date and node and server.
The filename has the following format done-PID-date.tar.bz2 (e.g. done-14143-2015-05-01.tar.bz2).

Usage: datafiles_tar_old_xml_files options

Supported options:
  -h Show this help.]]></ac:plain-text-body></ac:structured-macro>
<h2>Web front-end</h2>
<p>These scripts should be run as the DB_READ_USER user (<em>www-data</em> by default).</p>
<h3>Plotcache</h3>
<h4>plotcache_generate_cached_plots</h4>
<ul>
<li>
<p>You must add at least one option for which plot window to generate [-D|-W|-M].</p></li>
<li>
<p>By default, the cached plots are generated daily for the day before between 00:00 and 23:59. It can be helpful to configure a daily cron job to use this script to create cached plots to make loading of the homepage and common plots faster.&nbsp;</p><ac:structured-macro ac:name="note"><ac:rich-text-body>
<p><span>If not relying on the default behaviour be careful to specify BOTH a start and end date for this script, otherwise the end date will default to today and this may result in many plots being generated.</span></p></ac:rich-text-body></ac:structured-macro></li></ul><ac:structured-macro ac:name="code"><ac:parameter ac:name="language">text</ac:parameter><ac:plain-text-body><![CDATA[Create cached plots for each chosen period (day/week/month) between Start and End range of time.

Usage: generate_cached_plots options

Supported options:
    -s Start date of time range from which to create cached plots 
       (default is 1 day before at 00:00, format YYYY-MM-DDThh:mm)
    -e End date of time range from which to create cached plots 
       (default is 1 day before at 23:59, format YYYY-MM-DDThh:mm)
    -D Generate daily cached plots
    -W Generate weekly cached plots
    -M Generate monthly cached plots
    -h Show this help]]></ac:plain-text-body></ac:structured-macro>
<h4>plotcache_rm_cached_plots</h4>
<ul>
<li>
<p>The user should not normally need to run this script, but is available in case problem are encountered with cached plots, or it is desirable to flush the cache for some reason (for example the default interactive plot type is changed after graphs have been cached).&nbsp;</p></li>
<li>
<p>This script is interactive if the -a option is not selected.&nbsp;You will be asked to select which cached plot types you'd like to remove.</p></li></ul><ac:structured-macro ac:name="code"><ac:parameter ac:name="language">text</ac:parameter><ac:plain-text-body><![CDATA[Remove all or a set of cached plots from the directory structure.
 
Usage: plotcache_rm_cached_plots options

Supported options:
  -a Remove all cached plots
  -h Show this help]]></ac:plain-text-body></ac:structured-macro>
<h3>RSSAC</h3>
<h4>rssac_generate_reports</h4>
<ul>
<li>By default the script creates RSSAC reports for all configured servers for a date 7 days in the past</li>
<li>It will require that the&nbsp;database_process_rssac_data script will have already been run for the date in question.<em>&nbsp;</em></li>
<li>Note the unique_source data for the report is taken from the summary table, not the raw table.</li></ul><ac:structured-macro ac:name="code"><ac:parameter ac:name="language">text</ac:parameter><ac:plain-text-body><![CDATA[Create RSSAC reports for a specified 24 hour period
 
Usage: rssac_generate_reports options

Supported options:
  -d Date on which to create RSSAC reports 
     (default is 7 days ago, format: YYYY-MM-DD)
  -h Show this help]]></ac:plain-text-body></ac:structured-macro>
<h2>Other tools</h2>
<h3>conf_read</h3>
<ul>
<li>The script parses the contents of the <em>&lt;prefix&gt;/etc/hedgehog/hedgehog.yaml</em> file into environment variables for use my the other scripts. Users will not need to run this directly.</li>
<li>The database parameters are to be set by the user (if default ones need to be modified) and the directory structure parameters are auto-generated and better left alone.</li></ul>